Philipp Welsch

pwelsch86@gmail.com

Software -

Homepage

Engineer

LinkedIn

In a nutshell

I'm a programmer who acts as a generalist with a strong interest in computer graphics. My experience ranges from game engine development for PC and consoles over VR development to maintaining front- and back-end systems for customer- and user-facing applications.

Experience

d3t LTD / Core Tech Programmer

January 2018 - Present, Cheshire, England

- Building and maintaining high-performance systems written in C++ and C.
 Optimizing titles for both CPU and GPU side performance.
- Rendering and Xbox One platform support for a major UE4 title.
- Developing new features and improvements across all aspects and systems of games, across multiple major engines, both proprietary and openly available.

Polycular OG / Intern Programmer

July 2016 - December 2016, Hallein, Austria

- Designed, implemented and maintained core libraries used across multiple projects.
- Worked on multiple Unity3D applications for mobile and desktop.
- Implemented core frameworks, game logic and and user interfaces for Alternate Reality and location-based experiences.

Major League Gladiators / Lead Student Developer

November 2016 - April 2018, Global

A multiplayer VR coop FPS for HTC Vive built with Unreal Engine 4.

- Designed and implemented systems for other programmers to build upon
- Extended and maintained a custom build of Unreal Engine 4.
- Created and evolved the game design.

Education

FH Salzburg / BSc with honors, Multimediatechnology

September 2014 - July 2017, Salzburg, Austria

Computer Science with a major focus on software engineering, game programming and image processing. **Thesis**: Exploring the Applicability of Data-Oriented Design to Scene Graphs for Rendering